What do Euclid,
欧几里得有什么？
twelve-year-old Einstein,
爱因斯坦12岁
and American President James Garfield have in common?
和美国总统詹姆斯·加菲尔德有共同点吗？
They all came up with elegant proofs for the famous Pythagorean theorem,
他们都为著名的毕达哥拉斯定理带来了优雅的证明，
the rule that says for a right triangle,
规定在现有三角形中的规则
the square of one side plus the square of the other side
第一面的长度的平方加第二面的长度的平方
is equal to the square of the hypotenuse.
平方等于斜边的长度。
In other words, a²+b²=c².
换句话说，a²+b²=c²
This statement is one of the most fundamental rules of geometry,
这是几何学中最基本的规则之一，
and the basis for practical applications,
以及许多实际应用的基础
like constructing stable buildings and triangulating GPS coordinates.
例如固定建筑物的建造和GPS坐标的三角测量。
The theorem is named for Pythagoras,
该理论以毕达哥拉斯命名。
a Greek philosopher and mathematician in the 6th century B.C.,
公元前6世纪的希腊哲学家和数学家，
but it was known more than a thousand years earlier.
但是它在一千多年前就被人们所知。
A Babylonian tablet from around 1800 B.C. lists 15 sets of numbers
追溯到公元前1800年的巴比伦平板电脑包含15组数字的列表
that satisfy the theorem.
符合理论的文字。
Some historians speculate that Ancient Egyptian surveyors
一些历史学家推测，古埃及测量师
used one such set of numbers, 3, 4, 5, to make square corners.
使用3组，4组和5组方角之一。
The theory is that surveyors could stretch a knotted rope with twelve equal segments
从理论上讲，测量员能够将打结的绳索拉成12个相等的部分
to form a triangle with sides of length 3, 4 and 5.
形成边3、4和5的三角形
According to the converse of the Pythagorean theorem,
根据勾股定理的逆，
that has to make a right triangle,
它必须是直角三角形，
and, therefore, a square corner.
这意味着一个直角。
And the earliest known Indian mathematical texts
已知最古老的印度体育文字
written between 800 and 600 B.C.
写于公元前800年至600年之间
state that a rope stretched across the diagonal of a square
它指出一根绳子延伸到一个方形直径
produces a square twice as large as the original one.
它是原始盒子的两倍的盒子。
That relationship can be derived from the Pythagorean theorem.
这种关系可以从毕达哥拉斯的理论中推断出来。
for every right triangle on a flat surface,
对于平面上的所有三角形，
not just the ones these mathematicians and surveyors knew about?
不仅仅是运动员和测量师知道的三角形？
Because we can prove it.
因为我们可以证明这一点。
Proofs use existing mathematical rules and logic
证明使用现有的数学规则和逻辑
to demonstrate that a theorem must hold true all the time.
甚至该理论在所有情况下都成立。
One classic proof often attributed to Pythagoras himself
毕达哥拉斯本人经常提出的传统证据之一
uses a strategy called proof by rearrangement.
他使用一种称为“通过重新排列证明”的策略。
Take four identical right triangles with side lengths a and b
取四个边长分别为a和b的直角三角形
and hypotenuse length c.
长度为c的水。
Arrange them so that their hypotenuses form a tilted square.
排列它们，使它们的腱形成对角正方形。
The area of that square is c².
这个广场的面积是c²。
Now rearrange the triangles into two rectangles,
现在，将三角形重新排列为两个矩形，
leaving smaller squares on either side.
在侧面留下两个较小的正方形。
The areas of those squares are a² and b².
这些正方形的面积是a²和b²。
Here's the key.
这是关键。
The total area of the figure didn't change,
形状的总面积没有变化，
and the areas of the triangles didn't change.
三角形的面积没有改变。
So the empty space in one, c²
所以第一个自由空间c²
must be equal to the empty space in the other,
必须等于其他可用空间，
Another proof comes from a fellow Greek mathematician Euclid
另一个证明来自希腊数学家欧几里得
and was also stumbled upon almost 2,000 years later
大约2,000年后也发现了它
by twelve-year-old Einstein.
12岁的爱因斯坦。
This proof divides one right triangle into two others
该证明将现有三角形分为两个
and uses the principle that if the corresponding angles of two triangles
它使用这样的定律：如果两个三角形的对称角相等，
So for these three similar triangles,
在这三个相似的三角形中
you can write these expressions for their sides.
您可以像这样表达他们的边长。
Next, rearrange the terms.
然后，重新排列边框。
And finally, add the two equations together and simplify to get
最后，将两个方程式相加并简化结果以得到
ab²+ac²=bc²,
ab²+ac²=bc²，
or a²+b²=c².
或a²+b²=c²。
Here's one that uses tessellation,
这是马赛克重复的证明，
a repeating geometric pattern for a more visual proof.
重复的几何图案可提供更直观的证明
Can you see how it works?
看到了吗？
Pause the video if you'd like some time to think about it.
如果您想花更多时间考虑一下，请停止播放视频。
Here's the answer.
这就是答案。
The dark gray square is a²
深灰色正方形是a²
and the light gray one is b².
浅灰色为b²。
The one outlined in blue is c².
被蓝色包围的另一个是c²。
Each blue outlined square contains the pieces of exactly one dark
每个蓝色方块都包含一个深灰色的方块
and one light gray square,
还有另一个浅色盒子，
proving the Pythagorean theorem again.
因此重申了毕达哥拉斯的理论。
And if you'd really like to convince yourself,
如果您想完全说服自己，
you could build a turntable with three square boxes of equal depth
您可以创建一个旋转表，其中包含三个等深的方形框
connected to each other around a right triangle.
围绕现有三角形连接在一起。
If you fill the largest square with water and spin the turntable,
如果您将较大的盒子装满水，然后翻转桌子，
the water from the large square will perfectly fill the two smaller ones.
大盒子里的水将完全填满两个较小的正方形。
The Pythagorean theorem has more than 350 proofs, and counting,
毕达哥拉斯的理论有350多个证明，而且越来越多
ranging from brilliant to obscure.
介于杰出和神秘之间。
Can you add your own to the mix?
您可以向小组添加自己的证据吗？